(西伦敦最佳)
天啊
Oh, boy.
早上好 伙计们 抱歉我迟到了
Morning, fellas. Sorry I'm late.
我需要理一下思绪 所以我决定走路来上班
Just needed to clear my head so I decided to, you know, walk to work.
结果我发现在一个不太了解的城市 边走边理思绪
Turns out that clearing and walking in a town you don't know all too well
难度有点大
can be a little tricky.
最后我迷路了 但是之后 我又迷路了
Ended up getting lost but, you know, then I got unlost,
第三次迷路了 但是...
then I got lost again but...
我还是到这儿了 彼尔德在 内特也在 这很好
Well, you know, now I'm here, you know. Beard's here, Nate's here, which is great
因为这世界可能是一个 悲伤孤独的地方 但是...
because the world can be a sad, lonely place, but--
嘿 不说那些了 开始工作吧?
Hey, come on now, let's get to work, shall we?
米歇尔
Michelle.
没关系
Which is fine.
没关系 因为我正好可以
You know, it's okay, 'cause it's a great time now for me to,
把自己埋在工作里
you know, bury myself in my work here.
所以...不过 我没疯...
And so-- Although, I'm not crazy--
我不喜欢“埋”这个词 明白我的意思吧?
I don't love the word "bury," you know what I mean?
听上去就不是很吉利 对吧?
It's just got a negative connotation to it, don't it?
我能换成哪个词呢?
What's another word I could say?
所有人都喜欢泡澡 对吗? 舒服的热水澡 是吧?
Everyone loves a good bath, right? Just a nice warm bath, right? Yeah?
我就用这个词好了 我要说 “我要把自己泡在工作里”
So that's what I'll say. I'll say, "I'm gonna bathe myself in work."
怎么样?听上去好多了 很好
How 'bout that? That's good. That's good.
内特 你有喜欢的气泡弹吗 伙计?
Nate, you got a favorite bath bomb, buddy?
没有 我不是很喜欢泡澡 因为皮肤会泡得皱皱的
No, I just don't really enjoy baths, just 'cause my skin gets really wrinkly,
而我非常担忧变老这件事
and I'm deeply worried about aging.
好吧 我理解 你呢 教练? 你有没有喜欢的气泡弹?
Okay, I get that. What about you, Coach? You got a favorite bath bomb?
焦糖奶油蜂蜜
Crème brûlée honey.
蜂蜜?这是一种成分 还是你觉得我和蜜一样甜?
Honey? Is that an ingredient or something you just called me?
-成分 -该死
-Ingredient. -Shoot.
我还以为是后者呢 但这个主意挺有趣的
I was hoping it was the other one. But that's kind of a fun idea.
也许我们可以用昵称来称呼彼此
Maybe we start calling each other little pet names.
比如说“亲爱的”或是“宝贝”
You know? Like "honey" or "babe," you know?
挺不错的吧?你觉得呢 教练?
It might be nice, right? What do you think, Coach?
内特 能帮我个忙吗?
Nate, will you do me a favor here?
你能帮教练计划一下今天的训练吗?
Will you just help Coach plan practice for today?
-好的 没问题 -很好 谢谢 亲爱的
-Absolutely. Yeah. -All right. Thank you, sweetie.
好了 一会见
Okay, I'll see y'all in a little bit.
-他没事吧? -有事
-Is he all right? -No.
(♪我们是里士满)
好了 开始吧 萨拉 你来开个头吧?
All right. Shall we? Sarah, why don't you lead us off?
拉索教练 你终于赢了你的第一场比赛
So, Coach Lasso. You finally won your first match.
感觉如何?
How's it feel?
萨拉 我相信有时即使比分赢过对手 但依然是输家
Well, Sarah, I believe you can outscore your opponent and still lose.
正如即使你比分比对手更少 你也依然是赢家
Just like you can score less than them and win.
但上周我们确实赢了 非常令人开心
But last week we definitely won, which is pretty darn fun.
好了 下一个问题
All right, next question.
《独立报》的特伦特克里姆
Trent Crimm, <i>The Independent</i>.
是否可以猜测杰米塔特 下一场比赛会回到球场?
Is it safe to assume that Jamie Tartt will be back on the pitch next match?
你知道人们对猜测这件事 怎么说的吗 特伦特?
Well, you know what they say when you assume, Trent?
你把咱俩都变成了傻子
You make an arse outta you and me. Yeah?
这是另一个经典案例
And that right there is another example
我们的英语和你们的英语 有时候并不兼容 对吗?
of how our English and y'all's English sometimes do not jive, innit?
但你真的打算让最好的球员坐冷板凳吗?
But are you honestly gonna keep your best player on the bench?
这取决于杰米 他知道我们需要他做什么
Well, that depends on Jamie. He knows what we need from him.
下一个问题 奇普 问吧
Let's keep it going, yeah? Kip, come on, hit me.
-泰德 我正好要找你 -嘿 老板
-Ted. Just the man I wanted to see. -Hey, boss.
你让杰米塔特坐冷板凳的决定 真的非常勇敢
Your decision to bench Jamie Tartt was very brave.
-谢谢 -这是一招妙棋
-Thank you. -I mean, a masterstroke.
我想这种说法已经过时了吧
I don't think we're allowed to talk like that at work anymore.
但是有一件事比较棘手
There's just one complication now.
曼城打电话来
Manchester City have called,
他们想问能不能终止杰米的租借
and they've inquired about terminating Jamie's loan.
-他们要收走他的房子? -不是
-They're gonna take his house? -No.
泰德 杰米的合同是和曼城签的
Ted, Jamie's contract is owned by Manchester City,
他们这个赛季把他借给了里士满
and they, in turn, loaned him to Richmond for the season.
好吧 我懂了
Okay. I get it.
如果你让他坐冷板凳 他们计划收回他
They want Jamie back if you are planning to bench him.
我不是这么计划的 我计划让我的计划成功
I'm not planning on that. No, my plan is for my plan to work.
但俗话说得好 人算不如天算 对吗?
But you know what they say about the best-laid plans, right?
说太多遍“计划”了 我快不认识这个词了
Said "plan" too many times. Word's lost all its meaning now.
计划 计划 计划 无所谓了
Plan. Plan. Plan. Doesn't matter.
你跟曼城说 这个人另有计划
Hey, you tell Man City that this man has a plan.
-计划 计划 计划? -计划
-Plan. Plan. Plan? -Plan.
-计划? -嘴不要咧开
-Plan? -Not plan.
-计划 -类似“果酱馅饼”的发音
-Plan. -Like "flan." Plan.
果酱馅饼?那道甜品吗?
Flan? That dessert?
对 果酱馅饼
Yes, like "flan."
我不太喜欢吃
No, I don't dig on flan.
计划 计划
Plan. Plan.
计划 计划?
Plan. Plan?
-只用声音交流了? -那叫什么来着?
-Word become a sound? -What's that called again?
-语义饱和 -对
-Semantic satiation. -Yeah.
好吧
Okay. All right.
那个新来的墨西哥孩子还没到?
Is that new kid from Mexico here yet?
-他在治疗他的膝盖 -好吧 很好
-He's getting treatment on his knee. -Okay, good.
-他叫什么来着? -丹尼罗哈斯
-What's his name again? -Dani Rojas.
这名字不错 好的
Yeah. It's a great name. Okay.
杰米怎么样了?
How's Jamie doing?
怎么了?
What?
他说他受伤了 今天不能参加训练
Says he can't practice today. Says he's hurt.
要出事了
Oh, boy.
嘿 杰米
Hey, Jamie.
我听说你今天不能跟我们一起训练 是这样吗?
I heard you're not gonna be able to run with us today. That true?
对
Yep.
为什么?
Why's that?
因为我受伤了
'Cause I'm hurt.
很遗憾听到这个消息
Really sorry to hear that.
放松 泰德 只是训练而已
Relax, Ted. It's just practice.
嘿
Hey.
你说你不能训练 没问题
If you can't practice, you can't practice.
你说你受伤了 没问题 就这么简单
If you're hurt, you're hurt. It's as simple as that.
但这些都不重要
But it ain't about that... at all.
你坐在这里 你应该是球队的支柱
You're sitting in here. You're supposed to be the franchise player.
可我们却在讨论你缺席的训练
And yet here we are, talking about you missing practice.
我们谈的是训练
We're talking about practice.
明白了吗?训练
You understand me? Practice.
不是比赛
Not a game.
不是你去拼尽全力的比赛 对吗?
Not a game. Not the game you go out there and die for. Right?
周末也踢 仿佛是你最后一场比赛 对吗?
Play every weekend like it's your last, right?
不 我们谈的是训练 兄弟
No, we're talking about practice, man.
训练!你知道你应该参加的
Practice! You know you're supposed to be out there.
你知道你应该树立榜样
You know you're supposed to lead by example.
你把这些都抛在脑后了
You're just shoving that all aside.
所以 杰米 我们现在谈论的是训练
And so here we are, Jamie. We're talking about practice.
不是比赛
Not a game.
Not the game.
我们谈的是训练 和球队一起 和你的队友一起
We're talking about practice, with your team. With your teammates.
唯一一个我们可以一起踢球的地方 我们可以掌控的地方
The only place we get to play together, we got control over.
其余时间是我们11人 对阵对手的11人
Rest of the time it's us 11 against those 11.
我们谈的是训练 兄弟!
We're talking about practice, man!
我谈的是训练! 你参加不了 因为你受伤了
I'm talking about practice! And you can't do it 'cause you're hurt.
是吗?
Right?
我没意见
It's fine by me.
我跟你讲 帮我个忙
Tell you what. Do me a favor.
你出去的时候
When you get out there,
把锥形道具放好 这样其他人还能做一些传球练习
set up the cones so the other reserves can do a little passing drill.
-你让我放道具? -非常感谢
-You want me to set up cones? -I really appreciate it.
-科林 你去弄 -他点名要你去的 伙计
-Colin, go set the cones up. -I think he asked you, mate.
我在跟你说话吗 大块头?
Was I talking to you, big man?
科林 快去
Colin, set up the cones.
艾萨克说得对 教练让你去 你是替补队员
Isaac's right. He asked you. You are a second-teamer.
太伤自尊了
That's gotta sting.
再见
Cheers.
我必须得说 看到杰米被挫了锐气 我还挺开心的
I must say, it's quite nice seeing Jamie put in his place for once.
-甚至有些激动 对吗? -不
-Thrilling even, innit? -No, no, no.
不要幸灾乐祸 好吗?
This is a no schadenfreude zone, all right?
-不准幸灾乐祸 -好的
-<i>Nein schadenfreude.</i> -All right.
新来的那孩子 他叫...丹尼什么?
The new kid, what's his-- Dani what?
-罗哈斯 -罗哈斯 他踢得怎么样?
-Rojas. -Rojas, yeah. Is he any good?
夏季球员转会期过来的 随后就受伤了
Came here in the summer transfer window, was immediately injured,
-所以没人看过他踢球 -没关系
-so no one's really seen him play. -That's okay.
因为一旦杰米看到有人顶替了他的位置
You know, 'cause once Jamie sees someone else playing his position,
你知道...他会很不爽
you know... I mean, it's gonna hurt his soul.
很抱歉 我不应该这么开心的
I'm so sorry. I shouldn't be happy about that.
好的 我们要让但你尽快适应 好吗?
Okay, let's be sure to help Dani get acclimated, all right?
第一次加入这个球队肯定会不知所措
First time in this league can be very overwhelming.
丹尼罗哈斯 罗哈斯!丹尼罗哈斯!
Dani Rojas, Rojas! Dani Rojas!
罗哈斯 丹尼罗哈斯!罗哈斯!
Rojas, Dani Rojas! Rojas, Rojas, Rojas!
嘿!你们好 教练们
Hey! Hello, coaches.
-感谢你们给我这个机会 -你是一个很有活力的年轻人 丹尼
-Thank you for the opportunity. -Yeah. You are a spirited fella, Dani.
你去场上踢前锋看看 好吗?
Just go on out there, and get the striker spot for us, okay?
好极了!跟瓜达拉哈拉那时那样 你怎么说我就怎么做 教练
Yes! Just like back in Guadalajara, you say it, I do it, Coach.
足球就是生命!
Football is life!
我喜欢他
I like him.
杰米不喜欢
Jamie doesn't.
那种笨蛋一上场准露馅
Chipper dickheads like that can never back it up on the pitch.
漂亮的传球 山姆!
Beautiful cross, Sam!
足球就是生命!
Football is life!
天啊
Oh, boy.
你看到了吗?
Did you see that?
我也说不准 感觉他蛮厉害的
I can't really tell, but it seems like he's very good.
再见
Cheers, again.
一些待业的教练问我们近期有没有空缺
And some unemployed gaffers are asking if we'll have an opening soon.
托尼普利斯 阿兰科比什利 哈瑞雷德內普打过三次电话了
Tony Pulis. Alan Curbishley. Harry Redknapp called three times.
嗨 我昨晚一夜没睡 仔细研究了所有球员的背景
Hi. I've been up all night doing deep dives on all the players.
你知道理查德是在一个牧羊场长大的吗?
Did you know that Richard was raised on a goat farm?
还有 艾萨克的妈妈有两只左手?
And that Isaac's mother has two left hands?
我还联系了几个熟人 了解了一下赞助机会
And I called a couple of contacts about some sponsorship opportunities.
我甚至还给自己弄了一个日程本
Even got myself a little work planner.
你就不能买个没有“独角兽”的吗?
You couldn't get one without the word "unicorn" written on it?
滚开啦 独角兽多可爱
Fuck off. It's adorable.
抱歉 我忍不住会想如果我让你滚 你会有什么反应
Sorry, I couldn't help but think how you'd react if I told you to F off.
-没事了 你出去吧 希金斯 -好的
-That'll be all, Higgins. -Of course.
看到你笑我真的很开心
I'm really glad to see that you're laughing.
我就是来看看你是否一切安好
I just came by to see if you're okay, really.
我为什么会不好?
Why wouldn't I be?
老天 你还没看新闻吧?
Oh, Christ. Have you not seen the news yet?
我本来是想来安慰你的 而不是把坏消息带给你
I really wanted to be the one to comfort you, not to break it to you.
你还记得那个漂亮女孩 叫贝克丝?
So, you remember that stunning girl, Bex?
庆典当日和鲁伯特一起离开的那位?
The one that Rupert left with the night of the gala?
你想让我假装她不是绝世大美女?
Do you really want me to pretend that she wasn't mad fit?
那我要谢谢你了
I'd appreciate it.
好吧 那个丑八怪 她叫贝克丝
Okay, well. That hideous cow, whose name's Bex,
-其实是个简称 她其实叫... -瑞贝卡
-which is actually short for... -Rebecca.
对 刚好你们同名
Yep, which is also your name, as you know.
所以媒体称她为...
So the press is calling her--
“新瑞贝卡” 该死
"New Rebecca." Shit.
不是
Nope.
媒体称她为“瑞贝卡” 而你是...
The press is calling her "Rebecca," and you're...
“老瑞贝卡”
"Old Rebecca."
-什么? -老瑞贝卡
-What? -Old Rebecca.
老瑞贝卡?
Old Rebecca?
别担心 你可以的
Don't worry about it. You've got this.
如果你撑不住了
And if you ever have a moment,
或是你应付不来了 你可以打给我 好吗?
or if you don't got this, then you just call me, right?
哇!你是故意的 对吧?
Wow! That was on purpose, yes?
对 听着 伙计
Yeah. Look, mate.
你很优秀 但在这里
You're good, yeah, but up here,
优秀和卓越是有区别的
there's a difference between good and great.
一比一 该你了 朋友
1-1. Your turn, <i>amigo</i>.
我靠
Fuck's sake.
好吧 看着 左门柱
Right, watch this then. Left post.
哇 厉害
Wow. That was good.
我知道
I know.
耶!
Yeah!
我很幸运
I got lucky.
-明天继续 杰米塔特? -再说吧
-Again tomorrow, Jamie Tartt? -We'll see.
足球就是生命!
Football is life!
丹尼罗哈斯 罗哈斯!丹尼罗哈斯!
Dani Rojas, Rojas! Dani Rojas!
天啊 我跟你讲 伙计
Oh, boy. I tell you, man.
我觉得我们特别幸运 就像是从一棵幸运树上掉下来
I feel like we fell out of a lucky tree, hit every branch on the way down,
掉进了一个装满现金 和先酸后甜的孩子们的水池
ended up in a pool full of cash and Sour Patch Kids.
杰米是王牌 对吗?
I mean, Jamie is an ace, right?
但是他的态度 让他变成了不受人待见的梅花7
You know, whose attitude turned him into a seven of clubs.
然后我们找了另一个孩子 帮他重新变成王牌
So then we bring in another fella to help turn him back into an ace
然后那个孩子自己也会变成王牌
and then that fella ends up being an ace himself.
所以现在我们有了两张王牌
And so now we got two aces.
王牌 王牌 该死的 我又开始了 我没救了
Aces. Aces. Oh, heck. I did it again. I'm stuck.
-王牌 -就是这个词 对吗?
-Aces. -That's the word, yeah?
-王牌 -王牌
-Aces. -Aces.
-王牌 -王牌?我也被你传染了
-Ace. -Aces? Oh, now I'm in there.
-是吧?好吧 -王牌?王牌
-See? Okay, good. -Aces? Aces.
-希望别传染给别人 -王牌
-I hope it's not contagious. -Aces.
-王牌 王牌 -王牌?王牌
-Aces. Aces. -Aces? Aces.
-王牌 -王牌
-Aces. -Aces.
-伊斯兰国 -不对 这发音像“伊斯兰国”
-Isis. -No, that sounds like "ISIS."
我确实说了“伊斯兰国” 我不是有意的
I did say "ISIS." I didn't mean to.
好吧 如果我们克隆了KISS乐队 的主音吉他手会怎样?
Okay, what if we cloned the lead guitarist from Kiss?
-你会有两个... -弗莱利
-You'd have two-- -Frehleys.
今天的天气真好 你不觉得吗?
It's lovely weather we've been having, don't you think?
我喜欢这个季节
I love this time of year.
-新鲜叶子的味道 -怎么了?
-All the smells of fresh leaves. -What's happening?
我只是假装咱俩在散步
I was just pretending that the two of us were on a walk.
我看书呢
I'm trying to read.
其实 我自己也经常看书 最近
I've been doing a lot of reading myself, actually, recently.
我读到了一个很棒的故事
I read this mad story
讲的是一个孩子在南伦敦的穷地方长大
about a kid who grew up in a shit part of South London.
很小的时候被送去桑德兰足球俱乐部踢球
And who got sent off to play as a child in Sunderland, of all places.
后来他被迫自己出钱发行了一张饶舌单曲
And who later was forced to rap his own verse in a charity single
歌名叫《大吉大利 今晚踢球》
which was called "Winner, Winner, Football Dinner."
那是为全球饥荒而写的
That was for world hunger.
我相信那是解药
And I believe it was the cure.
你怎么知道这些事的? 你这是在干吗?跟踪我吗?
How do you know all this anyway? What are you doing now? Stalking me?
不是 我在看所有球员的简介
No. I'm reading all the players' bios.
瑞贝卡让我去公关部帮忙
Rebecca's got me in to help with the team's PR.
你别来烦我 我不要当你的展示小马
Well, you leave me out of it. I'm not one of your show ponies.
你有属于自己的号码 人们鼓掌时你绕着场地走
You wear a number, trot around while people clap,
所以也不是很离谱
so I wouldn't be too high and mighty about it.
回见 罗伊
Later, Roy.
丹尼罗哈斯!丹尼!
Dani Rojas! Dani, Dani!
好的
Okay.
好的 我不太明白 到底发生了什么?
Okay, okay, I don't understand. What the heck happened, all right?
-你被什么绊倒了吗? -这就是问题所在 教练
-Did you trip over something? -That's the thing, Coach.
我没有绊倒 是有东西想绊倒我
I did not trip over something. Something tripped me.
看不见的东西
Something not there.
好吧 医生 去给他检查一下
Yeah. Okay, Doc. Let's go get him looked at.
好的 你没事
Okay. You're okay.
天啊 这都是我的错
God, this is all my fault.
我看见丹尼在训练前去了治疗室
I saw Dani go into the treatment room before training,
但我什么都没说
and I didn't say anything.
你犯了大错
That was a mistake.
你为什么不说?
How could you not say anything?
希望大家都跟他道过别了
Well, I hope you've all said your goodbyes,
-因为我们不会再见到他了 -嘿 够了!
-'cause we're never gonna see him again. -Hey, that's enough!
再有人阴阳怪气地说一句 我和彼尔德听不懂的话
One more person says something that me and Beard don't understand,
我就要像我儿子那样发脾气了
I'm gonna have one of my son's classic temper tantrums.
简单来说 他会给我起很多傻乎乎的外号
It's basically just him calling me a bunch of silly names,
比如说“蠢脑袋” 或是“粑粑脸”
you know, like, I don't know, "dummy head" or "poo-poo face"
或是“粑粑笨蛋” 或是...我不知道 我还漏了什么?
or "poo-poo dummy" or-- I don't know. What am I missing?
-“尿尿手指” -“尿尿手指”
-"Pee-pee fingers." -"Pee-pee fingers."
快点 有什么话就说
Come on, now. Spill.
治疗室被诅咒了
The treatment room is cursed.
-什么? -是真的
-What? -It's true.
为什么从来没有人告诉我?
Why is this the first time I'm hearing about this?
我想是因为要成年人承认
Well, I think it has a lot to do with grown men being embarrassed
他们相信这种迷信玩意太丢人了
to admit that they believe in all this hoodoo, voodoo, juju business.
-嘿 我不信的 -很好
-Hey, I don't believe it. -Okay, good.
那我们俩去看一下那个房间
Then me and you, we're gonna go look in that room.
-不行 -为什么?
-No. -Why not?
因为...不行
Because... No.
该死!老天爷
Heck! Oh, man.
丹尼一小时前在外面?
I mean, Dani was out there, what, an hour ago?
在球场上跑圈
Running circles on that pitch
像一只欢快的、皮毛发亮的金毛猎犬
like a joyous raven-haired golden retriever.
教练 美国是不是有很多漂亮的狗狗 被圈进起来
Coach, is it true in America you guys have so many beautiful dogs in pounds
有些会毫无理由地被处死?
that some get put down for no reason?
是这样的 山姆
That is true, Sam.
但很多女性歌手正在努力改变这一现状
But it's also something a lot of female singer-songwriters are trying to change.
听着 我们不会放弃丹尼罗哈斯 这一点你们可以放心
Look, we're not gonna put Dani Rojas down. I'll tell you that right now.
先生们 召集其他队员
Gentlemen, I need you to gather up the rest of the fellas.
因为我们要解除诅咒
'Cause we got ourselves a curse to reverse.
你们俩怎么了?
What the fuck's wrong with you two?
整个里士满球队都来了
The whole Richmond team's here.
我的天
Holy shit.
嘿 教练 杰米?
Hey, Coach. Jamie?
好吧
Okay. That's okay.
嘿 各位
Hey, guys.
伙计们 请注意
Hey, fellas. Fellas, listen up.
谢谢大家的到场
Thank you, guys, for coming out.
听着 我对这种事情不太了解
Look, I don't know a lot about this stuff, you know.
我不了解诅咒
I don't know about curses.
但有一件事我知道 诅咒不会永远有效
But I do know this, they don't last forever.
波士顿红袜队诅咒 结束了
Okay, look at the Boston Red Sox curse. That's over.
芝加哥小熊队 结束了
Chicago Cubs, over.
该死的 甚至马丁斯科塞斯都拿了奥斯卡
Heck, even Mr. Martin Scorsese finally won his Oscar.
但我想我们大家都同意
But I think we can all agree that <i>The Departed</i>
《无间道风云》不一定是他最好的作品
is not necessarily his best work.
-不是 -对
-No. -Yeah.
-最好的应该是《金钱本色》 -不 是《好家伙》
-That belongs to <i>The Color of Money</i>. -No, it's <i>Goodfellas</i>.
-我保留意见 -不对 是《纯真年代》 伙计
-Agree to disagree. -Nah, nah. It's <i>Age of Innocence</i>, bruv.
-《恐怖角》 -安静!
-<i>Cape Fear.</i> -<i>Silence</i>!
喂!你们齐聚在此的消息一传出去
Oi, once the word gets out you lot are in here,
这地方就会变成该死的动物园
this place will turn into a fucking zoo.
答案是《穷街陋巷》
And the answer's <i>Mean Streets</i>.
-对 有道理 -说得好
-Yeah. That's a good one. -Yeah.
你们是因为我身后这张海报来的
You're all here because of this poster behind me.
希金斯先生
Mr. Higgins.
“你是迅速、强健的球迷吗?”
"Are you a fast, fit, fan of football?"
这个头韵押得好
That's solid alliteration right there.
成百上千的海报
Hundreds of those posters
在1914年11月18日被张贴在里士满镇
were put up around Richmond on the 18th of November, 1914.
这是向立志成为
It was an invitation for young men
职业足球运动员的年轻人发出邀请
to try out to be a professional footballer.
据说那天会在体育场举行
It said to come to our stadium that day.
但那是一个谎言
And it was a lie.
1914年 战争肆虐 根本就没有选拔赛
In 1914, the war was raging. There was no tryout.
只有征兵人员 等着鼓励男孩们参战
Just recruiters, waiting to encourage those boys to fight the fight.
他们那天征召了四百人
They enlisted 400 lads that day.
他们当中只有少数人活着回来了
Very few of them came home.
他们入伍后...
And after they enlisted...
你知道他们在哪检查身体吗?
do you know where they went for their physical?
老天 是我们的治疗室 对不对?
Oh, Christ, it's our treatment room, isn't it?
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
嘿 不是 伙计们 不是那样的 好吗?
Hey, no, no, no. Hey, no, fellas. No, it was not, okay?
好吧 是这样 抱歉 我说谎了 我都不知道我干吗要说谎
It was. I'm sorry, I'm lying to ya. I don't even know why I'm lying.
抱歉 我只是想让大家冷静下来
I'm sorry. I just wanted y'all to take a breath for a second.
等等 你是要告诉我 我们这里有四百个鬼魂?
Wait, wait, wait. What you're telling me is that we've got 400 ghosts?
这也太多了
That's too many ghosts.
我们打不过他们
We cannot fight them all.
我们不必跟他们打 理查德
We're not going to have to fight them, Richard.
等等 教练 那我们怎么办?
Wait, so, Coach, how do we fix this?
-我们无法改变历史 -对 你说得对 我们改变不了
-We can't change the past. -No, Sam. No, we cannot.
但我们可以选择铭记历史
But we can choose to honor it.
那些年轻人 他们为国捐躯
Now, those young men, they made the ultimate sacrifice.
所以 我们也要牺牲一些东西才算公平
So I think it's only fair that we sacrifice something of our own.
我要你们每个人今晚回家
I'm gonna ask each and every one of you to go home tonight,
找到一些东西 一个物件
find something, an item.
对你们个人很重要的东西
Something personal. Something that you truly value.
在今天半夜带到俱乐部来
And I want you to bring it tonight to the clubhouse, at midnight.
得了吧 胡扯
No. That is bullshit.
我们都他妈得这么干!
We're all going to fucking do it!
好吧
All right.
你们队长发话了
That's your captain talking right there.
里士满!
Richmond! Richmond! Richmond!
我没说错吧
Told you.
里士满!
Richmond! Richmond! Richmond!
嗨 杰米 你找我什么事?
Hi, Jamie. What do you need?
宝贝 我说了这事很重要 不能去你家里说吗?
Babe, I said it was important. We can't go inside your house?
不行!不能去家里
No way! We can't.
咱俩唯一擅长的事就是做爱
Sex was, like, the only thing that you and I was good at.
我已经喝了三杯酒 这是巴甫洛夫条件反射
I've had three glasses of wine. It's Pavlovian.
巴甫洛夫?是什么?酒的牌子吗?
Pavlovian? What is that? Is that the wine?
宝贝 我们进车里说总行了吧?好冷
Babe, can we not at least just get inside my car? It's cold.
不行 你不记得我们车震过多少次了?
No. You don't remember how many times we shagged in this thing?
所以车也是巴甫洛夫?
So the car's also Pavlovian?
我好像明白了
Think I'm getting it now.
所以 到底什么事 杰米?
So, what's up, Jamie?
该死的泰德拉索
Fucking Ted Lasso.
他真的让你很头疼 是吧?
He's really gotten up your bum, hasn't he?
宝贝 他甚至不是什么正经教练
Babe, he's not even a real coach.
你知道我们今晚要做什么吗?
Do you know what we're supposed to do tonight?
某种愚蠢的献祭之类的神叨叨的玩意
Apparently, some bullshit sacrifice, show-and-tell bullshit.
-好吧 你要去吗? -不 我当然不去
-Okay. You gonna go? -No, 'course I'm not.
-其他人都去吗? -对 但我是杰米塔特
-Is everyone else doing it? -Yeah, but I'm Jamie Tartt.
我跟其他人不一样
I'm not like everyone else.
你觉得如果我和其他人一样随大流
Do you think that I could've got from a council estate in North Manchester
我会从曼彻斯特北部的公租房
to the Premier League,
升级到英超联赛吗?
if I did what everyone else did?
不会
No. I don't.
你是个斗士 杰米
You're a battler, Jamie.
真的很吸引人
It's really hot.
但或许有一天 你会停止
But maybe someday you should stop battling the people
和那些只是想关心你的人战斗
that just wanna help you.
我觉得你想让我进去
I feel like you want me to come in.
巴甫洛夫什么的
It's Pavlovian.
祝你今晚愉快 杰米塔特
Have a good night, Jamie Tartt.
(瑞贝卡!-老瑞贝卡)
进来
Come in.
打扰了 韦尔顿女士 我是山姆 山姆奥比桑亚 我为球队踢球
Excuse me, Ms. Welton. Hi, I'm Sam. Sam Obisanya. I play for the team.
是的 山姆 我知道你是谁
Yes, Sam. I know who you are.
有什么我能帮上忙的吗?
Is there something I can help you with?
这事说起来挺尴尬的 你今晚有空吗?
This is really awkward, but are you free tonight?
山姆 你的心意我了解 但是...
Sam, I am very flattered, but--
不 不是约会之类的
No, no, no. It's not for romance.
是为了去除那个诅咒 我能理解你为什么会误会
It's just to get rid of this curse. I can understand why you misinterpreted.
我是说 你这么漂亮
I mean, you're so lovely
肯定经常收到浪漫邀约
you must get romantic invitations all the time.
嘴真甜
That's nice.
天呐 我还得处理自己的诅咒呢 不过 谢谢你
Gosh, I'm dealing with my own sort of curse. Anyway, thank you.
我来自尼日利亚 所以我感觉每次诅咒这种话题一出现
I'm from Nigeria, and so I feel like whenever the subject of curses comes up,
人们都会说:“我猜非洲小子 肯定很热衷这种事”
people are like, "I bet the African guy is really into this."
-你显然不是? -不 我是
-You're obviously not? -No, no, no. I really am.
但那主要是因为我喜欢哈利波特
But that's mainly from loving Harry Potter.
你知道JK洛琳比女王还富有吗?
Do you know J.K. Rowling has more money than the Queen?
我知道
I did.
我很喜欢一个人通过创造来获得财富
I like the idea of someone becoming rich, because of what they gave to the world.
而不是因为出身显赫家族
Not just because of who their family is.
韦尔顿女士 我希望你可以参与
Well, Ms. Welton, I really hope you can participate in this ceremony
我们今晚举行的仪式
that we're having later tonight.
我就算了吧
I don't think so.
很抱歉 我不接受拒绝
I apologize, but I can't take no for an answer.
教练认为整个团队的人都到齐了才有用
Coach thinks it will only work if the whole team is there,
韦尔顿女士 这是你的团队啊
and Ms. Welton, it's your team.
所以你必须到场 求你了
So you have to be there. Please.
至少考虑一下吧
At least think about it.
看在你的面子上 我会的 山姆
For you, Sam, I will.
谢谢
Thank you.
今晚见
See you tonight.
再见
See ya.
先生们 我是一个有神论者
Gentlemen, I am, by nature, a believer.
鬼魂、指导灵、外星人
Ghosts, spirit guides, aliens.
但我仍然没办法告诉你们
Still, I can't actually tell you
在我们生活的实体世界之外存在什么 不存在什么
what lives beyond our physical world and what doesn't.
我能告诉你们的是
What I can tell you,
除了《卡尔文和霍布斯》
is that with the exception
的聪明和智慧外
of the wit and wisdom of <i>Calvin and Hobbes</i>,
没有什么会永存
not much lasts forever.
-嗨 老板 很高兴有你的加入 -你好
-Hey, boss. Glad you could join us. -Hello. Yeah.
罗伊 你来开始吧?
Roy, why don't you get things started for us?
我九岁时被桑德兰的球探发现了
I was nine when I got scouted by Sunderland,
在那之前我从未离开过伦敦
and I'd never left London before.
我祖父开了很久的车把我送过去 那天非常冷 我怕得要死
My granddad drove me all the way there, and it was freezing, and I was terrified.
我他妈才九岁好不好 再说试试
I was fucking nine. Say something.
我到了之后 他把这块旧毯子给了我
When I got there, he gave me this old blanket.
他说这能给我温暖 让我有家的感觉
He said it was to keep me warm and to remind me of home.
那是我最后一次见到他
And that was the last time I saw him.
因为我圣诞节回去的时候 他已经过世了 所以...
'Cause he'd passed away by the time I got back for Christmas, so...
毯毯对我有很重要的意义
That is why blankie means so much to me.
你刚才说的是“毯毯”吗?
Did you just say "blankie"?
没有 我说的是“毯子” 谈话结束 山姆 该你了
No, I said "blanket." Conversation over. Sam, go.
这是1994年尼日利亚世界杯球队合影
This is a picture of the 1994 Nigerian World Cup team.
我发过誓 在我成功加入球队之前 我不会把这张照片拿下来...
I pledged I wouldn't take this down until I made the team myself...
但我还是打算这么做
and I still intend to do that.
这是一瓶圣巴泰海滩的沙子
This sand is from a beach in St. Barts.
这是第一个...
This is the first beach where I ever...
第一个我跟超模爱爱的海滩
It's the first beach where I ever slept with a supermodel.
-你应该开心 因为你赚到了 -谢谢
-Smile because it happened. -Thanks.
山姆和理查德让你体会什么是哭笑不得
Sam and Richard coming at ya from both ends of the spectrum there.
谢谢
Appreciate that.
一个女孩曾经说过 我戴这眼镜很像克里夫欧文
A girl once said I look like Clive Owen in these sunglasses.
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can do it.
-拜托 内特 扔进去吧 -你可以的 内特 扔进去
-Come on, Nate. Throw 'em in. -You got it, Nate. Give it a toss.
-很好 -好孩子 内特
-Nice. -Good boy, Nate.
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
那是今天的报纸吗?
Is that today's paper?
和往常一样 上面登了一些关于我的内容 我在努力不介怀
There's something in there about me, as usual, and I'm trying not to care.
去死吧 喷子
Fuck the haters.
同意
Word.
这是我家猫的项圈 它忠诚地陪伴了我20年
This is my cat's collar. She was a faithful companion for 20 years.
我会想念你的 辛迪爪爪福德
Gonna miss you, Cindy Clawford.
我只用这支笔签名
It's the only pen I can write my name with.
我的兰博基尼的车钥匙
The keys to my Lamborghini.
那你怎么回家?
How you getting home?
-好了 所有人都扔过了吗? -嗯
-All right. Everybody go?
-是的 -没有 我也想扔
-Yeah. -No. I wanna go.
这不是我的第一双球鞋 是我妈给我的
These aren't my first boots or anything. My mum gave 'em me.
我是因为她才爱上了足球
She was the one who got me into football in the first place.
我还是一个帅气的小婴儿的时候 她和我爸就离婚了
Her and me dad split up when I was just a sexy little baby.
为了她我努力工作 因为我想让她为我骄傲
She's the reason I work so hard. Just wanted to make her proud.
但她根本不在乎我是否优秀
She doesn't even care if I'm any good.
她只希望我快乐 做一个好人
Just wants me to be happy. Be a good lad.
等我的事业有了起色 我老爸再次出现了
Once I got good though, me old man started showing up, didn't he?
每次我进了球 都要跟他那些兄弟吹嘘
You know, bragging to all his mates every time I scored a goal.
如果我没能在球场压制对手 就叫我“软蛋”
Calling me "soft" if I didn't... dominate, you know.
我很讨厌这样
And I hated that.
我真的非常讨厌
I actually fucking hated that.
所以 我发誓我一定要变得很强 让他再也没法叫我“软蛋”
So, I made a vow to be so tough that he could never call me "soft" again.
我有时也在想...
I wonder if sometimes...
我忘记了让我妈妈感到骄傲
I forget about making her proud.
我想她最近会失望吧
I don't think that she would be lately.
先生们...
Well, gentlemen...
我们一把火把这些都烧了怎么样?
What do you say we burn this crap?
也许我们应该把这部分挪到室外
Maybe we should do this part outside.
-对 -这个建议好
-Yeah. -That's a good call.
好的 很机智
Yeah. That's smart. Okay.
你们介意帮我抬一下吗?
Hey, would you guys mind grabbing this for me?
打扰一下 泰德 已经准备就绪
Excuse me, Ted. The eagle has landed.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, fellas.
我想测试诅咒是否去除的唯一方法
I think the only way to know if the curse has been lifted or not,
是向神灵要一个信号
we need to ask the spirits for a sign.
噢 神灵...
Spirits...
显灵吧
speak to us.
丹尼罗哈斯!罗哈斯!丹尼罗哈斯
Dani Rojas! Rojas! Dani Rojas.
我带了一瓶麦斯卡尔酒丢进诅咒之火
I brought a bottle of mezcal to throw into the curse fire.
嘿 罗哈斯 听着
Hey, hey, hey. Rojas, look.
不管是什么鬼魂把你绊倒的
Whatever ghosts it were that made you trip over,
它们都消失了 我保证
they're gone now, I promise, yeah.
把这瓶酒打开
Crack that bastard open.
-耶 太好了! -好耶
-Yeah, boy! -Yeah.
杰米说得对 鬼魂更青睐我们喝完的空瓶子
Jamie's not wrong. Ghosts prefer empty bottles that we've all drunk.
这是事实
Fact.
我们来庆祝吧 朋友们
Let us celebrate, <i>amigos</i>.
这是一支团结一心的队伍
That is a team united.
你很幸运 丹尼的伤没事
You're very lucky that everything's fine with Dani's injury.
我从来不认为你是个赌徒 泰德
I just never had you pegged as a gambler, Ted.
我不是 我们几小时前就知道丹尼没事了
I'm not. We knew Dani's okay hours ago.
事实上 是希金斯的主意
In fact, it was my man Higgins' idea
在仪式之后再跟大家分享这个消息
not to share that info with the boys until after the ceremony.
-我很意外 -是的
-You don't say. -Yeah.
把球队放在第一位 是吗 希金斯?
Putting the team first, eh, Higgins?
我想是的
Yeah, I suppose I am.
嘿 教练 你不打算过来一起玩吗?
Hey, Coach, you joining the party or what?
你意下如何 老板?离火近点暖和
What do you say, boss? A lot warmer over there by the fire.
我就不过去了
I'll respectfully pass.
希金斯 你要来吗?
Higgins, coming with me?
你去吧
Off you go.
好的 这是什么情况?
All right now, what's this going on?
这里什么情况?
What's going on here? What's going on?
里士满至死不渝
Richmond till we die.
我们是里士满 至死不渝
We're Richmond till we die.
铭记于心 不曾怀疑
We know we are, we're sure we are.
我们是里士满 至死不渝
We're Richmond till we die. We're Richmond till we die.
铭记于心 不曾怀疑
We know we are, we're sure we are.
我们是里士满 至死不渝
We're Richmond till we die. We're Richmond till we die.
铭记于心 不曾怀疑
We know we are, we're sure we are.
我们是里士满 至死不渝
We're Richmond till we die. We're Richmond till we die.
铭记于心 不曾怀疑
We know we are, we're sure we are.
我们是里士满 至死不渝
We're Richmond till we die. We're Richmond till we die.
铭记于心 不曾怀疑 我们是里士满 至死不渝
We know we are, we're sure we are. We're Richmond till we die.
早上好 你们好吗?
Morning. How y'all doin'?
嘿 挺酷的
Hey. That's cool.
天呐 这是怎么了?
Oh, boy. Here we go.
我接住了
I got it.
拦截 轻点 先生们
Interception. Easy, gentlemen, easy.
早上好 亲爱的
Good morning, honey bunch.
听到外面的哄闹声了吗?我喜欢
You hear that buzz out there? I love it.
你还好吗?
How you doing?
你开除了杰米?
You got rid of Jamie?
曼城把他召回去的
Man City recalled him.
我跟你说过了 泰德 他们很担心他没球可踢
I told you, Ted. They were concerned he wasn't playing.
我终于打开了他的心门!
I finally got through to him!
你也看到了
I mean, you saw it.
有了他和丹尼 我们手里就有两张王牌 瑞贝卡
With him and Dani, we had two aces, Rebecca.
-我以为那是你想要的 -你想错了!
-I thought that was what you wanted. -Yeah, well, you thought wrong!
对不起 我为我的语气道歉 我太粗鲁了
I'm sorry. I'm sorry for my tone there, okay. That was rude.
听着 我也想冷静 但我眼前一片红色
Look, I'm trying to be cool about this, but I am just seeing red everywhere.
也许你应该出去 免得口无遮拦说出什么让自己后悔的话
Well, perhaps you should leave before you say something you'll regret.
不 你知道吗?这个给你
No, actually, you know what? Here you go.
你的饼干
Your biscuits.
我希望和往常一样好吃
I hope they're not as good as they usually are.
但是该死的 他们是我带过的最好的球员 我原本已经搞定了!
But dang it, they're the best batch yet. I finally cracked the recipe!
教练?
Coach?
足球就是生命
Football is life.
(塔特)
字幕翻译:肖雪